All right. So, we need some way of
getting result out of this function and
out into our main program. Well, um
let's think about how we've previously
gotten the result of a function out of a
function. Um if you think about when um
you replace text in a string, you said
let my new string equal
um old string.replace.
And then you probably put something here
and you replace it with something here.
Whoops.
Replaced it with something there. So
that would have taken the old string,
replaced those two things and stored it
in a new string. So how did it do that?
Well, the key here is that um
you set a variable equal to the result
of a function. And if you think about
it, you've done this a lot. You probably
said, "Let first name equal prompt."
Um, you've probably done other things
like that so far in this course where
you said, "Let my variable equal the
results of the function." So, if we want
to access result, we're going to have to
do something similar out here. So, we'll
say, "Let um
my results equal add two numbers." and
then we'll alert Whoops, sorry. We'll
alert my result.
So that's part of the solution. Part of
the solution is to take the result of
this, store it in a variable, and then
alert it. But what is the result of
this? Well, up here we called it result,
but JavaScript isn't smart enough to
know which part of this it needs to give
back to the main program. In order for
us to tell it what it needs to give
back, we need to use the keyword return.
So when you use the keyword return, it
ends this function and gives some
information out into the main program.
So it's going to send it to the other
side of an equal statement. So we could
say let my result equal and it's going
to be equal to whatever gets returned
here. Um right now we're not returning
anything, but we could say return
result. So what that will do is it will
take my m1 and then my m2 it'll add them
together and then it'll say return
result and it will take result and store
it in my result so that when we alert my
result we see the resulting value. I'm
going to um go live with this
and we can see that we got 30. So we've
successfully accessed result from inside
the program but let's watch that happen
in action.
Um, so we're going to come over here to
our sources tab and I'm going to put a
break point
right here on this line, line 22, and
I'm going to reload the page. Okay, it
has paused. Right now, my result is
nothing, but we're about to set it equal
to calling our function add two numbers.
So, I'm going to hit the next button,
and it's going to go into the function.
Um, it's going to say, so you'll notice
it jumped from line 22 up to line 13.
You'll hit next and my num one is now
10. We will hit next. My num 2 is now
20. Hopefully you know how to assign a
variable by now. Um, we'll add the
results together and result is now 30.
So if we hover over result, it is 30. If
we hover over my result, there's nothing
in it. We're going to hit the next
button.
And now if we hover over my result, it
has 30 in it. So it had exactly whatever
got returned from result is now stored
in my result.
Excuse me. You'll also notice that
because we're outside these curly braces
now, when I hover over result, it has
nothing in it. Um when I hover over my
result, it has the result of the
function, which is 30. And then if we
hit our next button, it alerts 30. So if
you want to um get information out of a
function and you want to use it in your
main program, the way you do that is you
use a return statement. Now this
function is probably not very useful
because right now all it's doing is
repeatedly adding 10 and 20. It'd be
nice if this function was a little more
flexible and we could give it our own
numbers to use. So, similar to how an
alert box doesn't show the same message
every time, and we can say hello world
and it will show hello world or we could
say um
I love ice cream um
and it will adjust the alert box. We
want our add to numbers to be flexible
just like that so that we can add
multiple different types of different
numbers rather than just always adding
10 and 20. And in the next video, we'll
talk about how to do